itbrain.com 2018-11-22

# TeamViewer Privacy Policy

## **TeamViewer Website Privacy Policy**

 **Introduction**  
We, the TeamViewer GmbH, take protection of your personal data very seriously. The following policy provides an overview of how we ensure this protection and what kind of data is processed for what purpose. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, such as your name, address, email addresses, user behavior. Further to this Website Privacy Policy, please refer to our product privacy policies for detailed information concerning your use of the various products.

A. Controller respectively Provider  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Web Analytics  
H. Remarketing Applications  
I. Social Media Plugins  
J. Integrated Third Party Service Tools  
K. Statutory/contractual requirement  
L. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
M. Your Rights

##  **A. Controller respectively Provider**

TeamViewer GmbH (“TeamViewer”), Jahnstr, 30, 73037 Göppingen, [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com), provides this website. In accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act, TeamViewer is controller of your personal data.

##  **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mr. Häcker as external data protection officer, who can be reached at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) or at [dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de](mailto:dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de) or at ENSECUR GmbH, to the attention of Mr. Julian Häcker, Rotebühlplatz 20A, 70173 Stuttgart.

##  **C. Categories of Data**

TeamViewer collects and processes different categories of personal data depending on the respective service used by you. The following paragraph outlines the categories of data processed by category of service.

###  **I. Use of TeamViewer’s website**

 **1\. Protocol Data:** When you visit the TeamViewer website for informational purposes, i.e. you are not logged into a TeamViewer account and/or register for any service or feature, we collect the following personal data transmitted by your server:

  * IP address
  * Date and time of the request
  * Time zone difference from Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  * Content of the request (specific site)
  * Access status / HTTP status code
  * Volume of data transmitted each time
  * Website from which the request comes
  * Browser
  * Operating system and its interface
  * Language and version of the browser software
  * The country of origin for the visitor

 **2\. Cookies:** Furthermore, when you visit our website, cookies are stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard disk in association with the browser you are using and through which specific information flows to TeamViewer. Cookies cannot initiate programs nor deliver viruses to your computer. They serve only to make the internet service more user-friendly and effective. This website uses the different kinds of cookies set out in our Cookies Policy https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies.

 **3\. Web analytics, social media plugins, remarketing tools and third party integrated services:** TeamViewer uses web analytic applications (please refer to G. for further information), remarketing tools for advertisement purposes (please refer to H. for further information), security features used for our product (please refer to I. for further information), social media plugins (please refer to J. for further information) and third party integrated services (please refer to K. for further information). By and through these applications and tools, the aforementioned personal data of our users are collected. For further information on those tools and applications, please proceed to relevant provision below and review the description provided there.

###  **II. Use of TeamViewer’s Contact our Sales Team**

 **First Name, Last Name, Email-address, Phone number, Country, Company, Subject, and Description: When you contact our sales team through our website contact form, TeamViewer will collect your first name, last name, email-address, country, subject and description; if you provide us with your **phone number, company information**** and other information marked as optional, we will also collect this information and use it for contacting you and serving your request. Wherever we collect your personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact privacy@teamviewer.com or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use. Please note that TeamViewer as a global company may receive messages that require translation. In such case, our employees use translation tools in order to process your inquiry. Thus, please ensure that you do not enter personal information into the subject line and description field of your inquiry.

###  **III. Submit a Ticket**

 **Email-address:** If you submit a ticket for your TeamViewer product or your TeamViewer IoT product, TeamViewer will process your email address.

###  **IV. Use of TeamViewer’s Feedback Feature**

 **E-mail-address, country of origin, and inquiry: When you contact us through the feedback feature on the website and/or within the product, TeamViewer will process your email address, your country of origin, and inquiry; if you provide us with additional information such as your **name, company information, phone number, license key** , as well your **TeamViewer ID**** , and/or any attachments to your inquiry, TeamViewer will also collect such information and use it to serve the request. Wherever we collect your additional personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

###  **V. Use of Quote Request Feature**

 **Name, address, email-address, company information: If you request a quote for one of our products, TeamViewer will collect your name, address, and email address, your company information, and product inquiry; if you provide us with additional information such as your **phone number** and your **country information**** , we will also collect such information and use it to serve the request. Wherever we collect your personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

###  **VI. Buy Now Feature**

 **Salutation, First name, Last name, Company, Country, Address, ZIP code, City, Phone, E-Mail Address, payment method (PayPal, Credit Card, Invoice, Debit Card) and Payment Token:** We will process your first name, last name, address, Zip code, city, phone, email address and your chosen payment method if you purchase TeamViewer product from our website. If you provide us with additional information such as a salutation, company, and country information, we will also process this information. The Payment Token will be provided by the Payment Service Provider as a record of the transaction. Required fields necessary to conclude the transaction are specially marked; any additional information is voluntary and based on your consent. Wherever we collect your personal data on basis of your consent, you may revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. Please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

###  **VII. Download through Apple App Store:**

If you click on the “Download on the App Store”-button to download TeamViewer, you are being forwarded to the Apple App Store, a service provided by Apple Inc., 1 Infinite Loop, Cupertino, California, USA, 95014. This means that Apple Inc. receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

###  **VIII. Download through Google Play:**

If you click on the “Get It On Google Play”-button to download TeamViewer to your Android phone, you are being forwarded to Google Play, a service provided by Google, Inc., Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. This means that Google, Inc. receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

###  **IX. Download through Microsoft:**

If you click on the “Get it from Microsoft”-button to download TeamViewer, you are being forwarded to the Microsoft App Store, a service provided by Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited (“ **Microsoft** ”), The Atrium Building Block B, Carmanhall Road, Sandyford Business Estate, Dublin 18. This means that Microsoft receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

###  **X. Download through Blackberry:**

If you click on the “Get it at BlackBerry World”-button to download TeamViewer, you are being forwarded to the BlackBerry Webstore, a service provided by BlackBerry (“ **BlackBerry** ”) 2200 University Avenue East, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada, N2K 0A7

This means that BlackBerry receives your personal data as stated under C. I. along with personal data relevant for any purchase, if applicable, and is controller of this data in accordance with Art. 4 par. 7 GDPR.

###  **XI. Newsletter Subscription**

 **Email-address:** If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer will collect your email address by obtaining your consent. Please note that TeamViewer uses the so-called double opt-in method by which you receive a confirmation email after you provided us with your email address to subscribe to our newsletter. If you do not confirm your email address within 24 hours, TeamViewer will delete your newsletter request. You may revoke your consent for the processing of your email address for newsletter receipt at any time with effect for the future. Please contact privacy@teamviewer.com or the respective method shown to you via the communication channel that you use.

###  **XII. Community**

Your personal data as outlined under **C. I. If you click on the community link, you will be forwarded to the TeamViewer community website. If you want to join TeamViewer’s community, you have to sign in and/or sign up with your TeamViewer credentials, such as your **email address** , your **name** , and a **password**. TeamViewer’s community website is powered by Lithium Technology, LLC (“ **Lithium** ”), which targets user data as well as content data so that TeamViewer receives information about most interesting topics chosen by website users. This means that your personal data as outlined under **C. I.**** will also be processed by Lithium. For further information on Lithium’s data processing, please refer to their privacy policy under <https://www.lithium.com/privacy>. You may comment publicly on different subjects concerning TeamViewer’s activities and products in TeamViewer’s community. Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name. We recommend to use an assumed name instead of your real name. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines; therefore, please check prior to posting if your comment contains personal data.

 **Name/assumed name, email-address, IP address:** If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s community, we will store your name/user name (depending on your choice), email-address, and IP address.

###  **XIII. Blog**

 **E-Mail Address:** TeamViewer will process your email address if you subscribe to our blog.

 **Name, Email-Address and Website:** If you want to post a comment in our blog, TeamViewer will process your name and email address; if you provide us with a website, we will also process this information. You may comment publicly on different subjects concerning TeamViewer’s activities and products in TeamViewer’s Blog. Your comment will be published in the relevant topic section by showing your user name. We recommend to use an assumed name instead of your real name. Please note that your comments are publicly accessible and will appear in search engines; therefore, please check prior to posting if your comment contains personal data.

###  **XIV. Servicecamp Feature**

 **Name, email-address:** If you want to use ServiceCamp, you will have to create an account. TeamViewer will collect your name and email-address.

###  **XV. TeamViewer Customer Council:**

If you participate in the TeamViewer Customer Council, we will collect your **name, **email address** and **user experience**** in a survey.

##  **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

To the extent TeamViewer is required to process any of your personal data in order to comply with a legal obligation we are processing your personal data on basis of Art. 6 par. 1 c) General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”).

 **I. Website use:** We want to ensure that when you visit any part of TeamViewer’s website your journey will be user-friendly, particularly that you do not encounter technical problems and malfunctions. In order to manage our relationship with you or your business we collect the following data to serve our business purposes such as

  * to understand the performance of our websites that hold TeamViewer product, business or support information;
  * to communicate with you about our products and services;
  * to develop and manage our brands, products and services;
  * to serve our business improvement needs;
  * to develop and carry out marketing activities.

Legal basis for processing personal data outlined under C. 1. is a user agreement concerning the use of our website, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **II. Contact our Sales Team:** If you place an inquiry with us by using the contact form, TeamViewer needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data is a service agreement, i.e. Art. 6 para 1 lit. b) GDPR. In case you submit additional data based on your consent, the legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

 **III. Submit a Ticket:** If you submit a ticket that concerns one of our products, we will process your personal data to answer your inquiry. We use this feature to fulfil our business purpose of authentication of our product users and provide service resolution for our customers. Legal basis for such processing is a service agreement and our contractual obligation to perform on our contract to provide you with our goods and services, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **IV. Feedback feature:** If you place an inquiry with us by using the in product support feature or through our website, TeamViewer needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request and to provide the requested support. Information collected in this way serves several business purposes including but not limited to

  * to test new products;
  * to manage how we work with other companies that provide services to us and our customers;
  * to develop new ways to meet our customer needs and to grow our business.

Legal basis for processing your personal data is a service agreement concerning the requested support and/or performance of the already existing agreement with you, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR. In case you submit additional data based on your consent, the legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

 **V. Quote request:** If you request a quote for our product, TeamViewer needs your personal data in order for us to process your request. Information collected in this way helps us

  * to develop products and services, and to convey what we charge for them;
  * to seek your consent when we need it to contact you; and
  * to be efficient about how we fulfil our legal and contractual duties.

Legal basis for processing your personal data is your request prior to entering into a contract, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **VI. Buy now feature:** If you purchase our product by said means, TeamViewer needs your personal data for the performance of a contract. This information is required for our business to serve the purpose of

  * to receive and manage customer payments; and
  * to collect and recover money that is owed to us.

Legal basis is therefore Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **VII. Apple App Store:** In order for TeamViewer to offer TeamViewer for Mac, we embedded a hyperlink to Apple Inc.’s App Store to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to the App Store is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **VIII. Google Play:** In order for TeamViewer to offer TeamViewer for Android products, we embedded a hyperlink to Google Inc.’s Play Store to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to Google Play is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **IX. Microsoft App Store:** In order for TeamViewer to offer TeamViewer for Microsoft products, we embedded a hyperlink to Microsoft’s App Store to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to Microsoft is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **X. BlackBerry:** In order for TeamViewer to offer TeamViewer for BlackBerry products, we embedded a hyperlink to BlackBerry’s World to which you are being forwarded. Legal Basis to forward you to BlackBerry’s World is our legitimate interest to provide a wide range of product compatibility according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **XI. Newsletter Subscription:** If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer needs your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. Newsletter help us to serve our business purposes such as

  * to manage our relationship with you or your business; and
  * to develop and carry out marketing activities.

Legal basis for providing you with the newsletter is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may revoke at any time with effect for the future.

 **XII. Community:** TeamViewer’s community helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform where issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. If you post a comment in our community, TeamViewer commissioned Lithium to process your personal data, so we understand what topics are most relevant to our users and for us to design our website user friendly and interesting. TeamViewer also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defence in the event that a third party complains about your community comment’s content. In such case, TeamViewer needs to be able to contact you. Legal basis for such processing is a user agreement concerning the use of our community and our legitimate interest of legal defense, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **XIII. Blog:** TeamViewer’s Blog helps us to satisfy our business purpose to assist product users with an open platform where issues, experiences and improvements can be shared and resolved. TeamViewer also processes your personal data so that we are able to raise a defense in the event that a third party complains about your Blog comment’s content. In such case, TeamViewer needs to be able to contact you. Legal basis for such processing is a user agreement concerning the use of our Blog and our legitimate interest of legal defense, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **XIV. ServiceCamp feature:** If you create an account in order to use ServiceCamp, TeamViewer needs your personal data to provide you with the service and for performance of the user contract, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **XV. TeamViewer Customer Council:** If you participate in the TeamViewer Customer Council as TeamViewer’s product user group, we will process your personal data for carrying out surveys to share user experience and knowledge. Legal basis is your consent, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit a) GDPR.

##  **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer may transfer your personal data to third parties if we offer participation in campaigns, contests, reservations, or contract agreements in conjunction with a third party. In this case, you will be specifically informed about the transmission to the third parties before your data is forwarded.

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction. TeamViewer employees, who administer, maintain and further develop TeamViewer’s product and services will receive access to your personal data.

If you use our **product, contact us through the **contact feature** , **support** and **feedback features** , if you request a **quote** , and/ or if you **subscribe to our newsletter**** , TeamViewer employees that are responsible for the respective service will receive access to your personal data.

If you post a comment in TeamViewer’s **community or **Blog** , your comment content and name/user name will be publicly available and may appear in search engines. Aside from TeamViewer employees, employees of Lithium may receive access to your personal data as described under **C. I.**** if comment in TeamViewer’s community.

If you purchase a TeamViewer product through our **Buy Now feature, TeamViewer employees are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. Please note that TeamViewer uses SSL technology encryption for payments to prevent unauthorized third party access to your financial data. If you download TeamViewer through the **Apple App Store** , employees of Apple Inc. receive access to your personal data as described under **C. VII.**. Similarly, if you download TeamViewer through **Google Play** , employees of Google Inc. receive access to your personal data as described under **C. VIII.**. If you download TeamViewer through **Microsoft** , employees of Microsoft Inc. receive access to your personal data as described under **C. IX.**. If you download TeamViewer through **BlackBerry** , employees of BlackBerry receive access to your personal data as described under **C. X.****.

In addition to services described under **G., **H.** , **I.** , and **J.**** , TeamViewer uses external third party service provider for maintenance and hosting of its IT-systems. TeamViewer has chosen such external third party service providers carefully. Furthermore, employees of such third party service provider will receive access to your personal data only within the scope of their job description, and are bound by TeamViewers directives concerning data processing. Furthermore, Google employees as well as employees of social plugins and integrated services, as described below, may receive access to your personal data. Please note that such data processing done by Google, social plugin providers, and integrated service providers is beyond TeamViewers control.

Except as mentioned under **G., **H.** , **I.** , and **J.**** , concerning data transfers to the USA and for group internal IT services provided from outside the EU, including Australia, US and Armenia, TeamViewer will not transfer your personal data outside the EU and/or EEA. TeamViewer will transfer your personal data only when required to so by law or orders from the relevant authority.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

##  **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

Your personal data will be deleted once you revoked consent, or the purpose for processing has ceased to exist. In some cases, TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain data for a certain period. Once this period has lapsed, TeamViewer will delete the data in accordance with data protection obligations.

 **I. Cookies:** Please click here https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies to access our Cookies Policy for further information.

 **II. Contact information:** TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain support feature requests from customers concerning product support inquiries in accordance with § 257 HGB and § 147 AO for a minimum of six and a maximum period of 10 years. With regard to personal data provided through contact requests, TeamViewer will retain such request for three months following closure of the request and delete such data thereafter.

 **III. Submit a Ticket:** Personal data provided in connection with a ticket submitted will be retained for as long as the ticket is open. Once your inquiry has been answered, TeamViewer will retain such data for a three (3) month period.

 **IV. Feedback feature:** Personal data provided in connection with feedback features are retained for three months following submission of feedback; TeamViewer will delete such data thereafter.

 **V. Quote request:** Personal data provided in connection with quote requests is retained by TeamViewer for three months following the period of quote validity, provided no ensuing contract was concluded. Provided the quote request lead to conclusion of a contract, please refer to F. II. for information on retention periods.

 **VI. Buy Now Feature:** Personal data provided in connection with a product purchase, i.e. address- and payment information as well as the order date, is retained by TeamViewer for a minimum period of six years in accordance with § 257 HGB, and a maximum period of 10 years in accordance with § 147 AO.

 **VII. Apple App Store:** Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under C. VII. will be retained by Apple Inc. Please refer to https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/ for further information.

 **VIII. Google Play:** Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under C. VIII. will be retained by Google Inc. Please refer to https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US&gl=de for further information.

 **IX. Microsoft:** Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under C. IX. will be retained by Microsoft. Please refer to https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement for further information.

 **X. BlackBerry:** Personal data processed in connection with a download as described under C. X. will be retained by BlackBerry. Please refer to https://de.blackberry.com/legal/privacy-policy for further information.

 **XI. Newsletter:** Personal data provided in connection with a subscription to our newsletter will be retained for as long as the subscription is valid. Upon revocation of your consent, your personal data will be deleted entirely.

 **XII. Community:** Personal data provided in connection with your community posts are retained for as long as you as you are a community member up until you deregister.

 **XIII. Blog:** Personal data provided in connection with your Blog subscription will be retained until you deregister.

 **XIV. ServiceCamp features:** Personal data provided in connection with ServiceCamp features are retained for as long as a user agreement is in place. Once you unsubscribe from ServiceCamp, TeamViewer will retain your personal data for three (3) months, and thereafter delete it.

 **XV. TeamViewer Customer Council:** Personal data provided during your participation in the Customer Council will be collected through surveys, stored in spread sheets and will deleted after three months.

##  **G. Web Analytics**

###  **I. Google Analytics**

TeamViewer uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Ireland Ltd. (“ **Google** “), with its business address at Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. Google Analytics uses “Cookies”, i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and enable analysis of your website use. TeamViewer uses Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIp()”. Thereby, IP addresses are processed in a shortened form and no direct reference to individuals is possible. TeamViewer uses Google Analytics to analyze and improve its website. TeamViewer receives statistics which help us to make our online presence more interesting for you. Legal basis to use Google Analytics is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The information generated by cookies about your use of this website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. If you enable IP anonymization on this website, your IP address from Google will be shortened within Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google has subjected itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield for any such exceptional cases in which your personal data will be transmitted to the USA; further information are available under [www.privacy-shield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework). Google will on behalf of TeamViewer use this information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activity, and provide other services regarding website and internet use to TeamViewer.

In addition, TeamViewer’s website uses Google Analytics for cross-device analysis of user streams, which are enabled through User-IDs. If you have a customer account, you may disable such cross-device analysis by <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010>.

The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of the Google Analytics will apparently not be merged with other data from Google.

As further explained in our Cookies Policy https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/?policy=cookies, you may block cookies from being stored on your device by adjusting the settings in your browser software; however, in such case, you may not be able to use all of the features and functionalities of our website. You can also block the collection of the data generated by the cookie and the data related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing a browser plugin available from the following link: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de).

Please visit the following homepage for an overview on data protection: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>, as well as the privacy policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

###  **II. Hotjar**

TeamViewer uses Hotjar heatmaps, recordings, funnels, forms and polls, services provided by Hotjar Ltd. St. Julian’s Business Center, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians 1000, Malta.

Hotjar is an all-in-one Analysis and Feedback tool that reveals the online behaviours and feedback of a website’s visitors. By combing both tools, Hotjar provides a big picture of how to improve website experience and performance. The analysis tools allow TeamViewer to measure and observe user behaviours (what users do) while the Feedback tool allows TeamViewer to obtain feedback.

Hotjar is built on anonymous insights and not on personal data. Site visitors are assigned a unique user identifier, so that Hotjar can keep track of returning visitors without relying on any personal information. When collecting data with Recordings, Hotjar also has automated suppression features in place and data is suppressed client-side, in the visitor’s browser, meaning personally identifiable information never reaches Hotjar servers keeping sessions private.

Data collected using Hotjar is stored in Ireland, using Amazon Web Services infrastructure. Data retention times is no longer than 365 days.

###  **III. Google Tag Manager**

Additionally, TeamViewer uses Google Tag Manager, tracking and conversion tool provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA

###  **IV. Google BiqQuery**

Provides a system for analysis of data sets generated by Google analytics.

###  **V. Google Display Feature**

Our website uses third party cookies from Google Analytics for Display Advertisers, including the following features. No personal data is processed within those services:

  *  **Remarketing with Google Analytics**  
The integrations between both our web analytics and paid advertising platforms together to give us additional insight. This allows us to tailor our advertising to ensure the right types and offers are shown to you while you are using the internet outside our website.
  *  **Google Display Network Impression Reporting**  
Which gives us additional insight into who has viewed our paid digital advertising on other websites. This will help us optimize and tailor our advertising.
  *  **Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting**  
Which gives us insight into behaviour information relating to visitor age, gender and interests on an anonymous and aggregate level. This will help us to understand browsing behaviour to give you a better experience whilst visiting our sites.

###  **VI. reCAPTCHA**

TeamViewer uses reCAPTCHA to protects our website from spam and abuse. reCAPTCHA is a service provided by Google that uses an advanced risk analysis engine and adaptive CAPTCHAs to keep automated software from engaging in abusive activities on our site. It does this while letting valid users pass through with ease.

reCAPTCHA allows TeamViewer to verify if an interaction is legitimate without any user interaction. It is a purely JavaScript API returns a score giving the us the ability to take action in the context of our site: for instance requiring additional factors of authentication, sending a post to moderation, or throttling bots that may be scraping content.

reCAPTCHA handles no personal information. Please visit the following page for an overview of reCAPTCHA <https://developers.google.com/recaptcha/>

### **VII. Google Optimize**

Google Optimize analyzes the use of different variations of our website and helps us to improve the usability according to the behavior of our users on the website. No personal data is processed.

###  **I. Google AdWords Conversion**

TeamViewer’s website uses Google AdWords, in order to generate attention for our services by using advertisement on third party websites. Based on data generated by such advertisement campaigns, we are able to determine the success rate of our advisement campaigns. Thereby, TeamViewer tries to provide you with advertisement that is of interest to you, to make its website more interesting, and calculates advertising expenses fairly. Legal basis for such processing of personal data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Such means of advertisement are delivered by Google through a so-called Ad Server. Along with this, TeamViewer uses Ad Server Cookies, which scale certain parameters, such as display of ads or clicks by users. Provided you clicked on an ad delivered by Google and which redirected you to our website, a cookie is stored on your computer by Google AdWords. These cookies usually expire within 30 days and are not supposed to be used to personally identify a user. In addition to these cookies, analytic values like unique cookie ID, quantity of Ad impressions per storing, last impression and opt-out information (markings that the user does not want to be addressed any further) are usually stored. These cookies enable Google to recognize your internet browser. If you visit certain pages on our website and provided the cookie stored on your computer has not yet expired, TeamViewer and Google are able to recognize that you clicked on an ad and were redirected to the TeamViewer website. Every Google AdWords customer gets a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked across sites by AdWords customers. TeamViewer does not process personal data by and through the aforementioned advertisement campaigns. TeamViewer merely receives statistical evaluations from Google. By and through these statistical evaluations, we can plainly see which advertisement campaign was particularly effective. Any additional data generated by use of the advertisement is not forwarded to TeamViewer; particularly, we cannot identify users through this information. Through the marketing tool, your browser automatically connects to Google’s server. Google has subjected itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield, further information can be obtained under www. www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework. Please note, that scope and further use of the data processed by Google are beyond TeamViewer’s control. We thus inform you based on our own knowledge: By integrating AdWorks, Google receives information that you visited a particular TeamViewer website or part thereof, and/or that you clicked on one of our advertisements. If you are registered with one of Google’s services, Google is able to match your visit to your Google account. Google may receive your IP address and/or may store it even if you are not registered with one of Google’s services and/or if you have not been logged in. You may avoid tracking in various ways:

a) Through a setting of your browser software, particularly, by suppressing third party cookie installation that will prevent that you receive third party ads;

b) Through deactivating AdWorks Cookies, by setting your browser so that cookies from www.googleadservices.com are being blocked; this can be done under <https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous>, however, such settings are deleted if you delete cookies;

c) Through permanently deactivating cookies in your Firefox, Internet Explorer or Google Chrome under <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996>. Please note that if you deactivate these cookies, you may not be able to use all functionalities of our website.

Further information on Google’s data privacy can be found under www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy. Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies for interest-based advertising via the advertising network initiative, by following the instructions at <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/>.

###  **II. Google Remarketing**

TeamViewer uses Google Remarketing in addition to AdWords. This is an application that allows us to address you again. After visiting our website and while you are surfing the internet, our advertisement can be displayed to you by and through this application. This is enabled by cookies stored in your browser which track and analyse user behavior on different websites for Google. Google can track your previous visit to our website. According to its own statement, Google does not combine data gathered through remarketing with any personal data Google may have stored about you. Furthermore, pseudonymization is being used as part of remarketing. If you do not want to use the remarketing feature from Google, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at <https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous>.

###  **III. A/B-Testing**

TeamViewer additionally uses A/B-testing provided by Optimizely GmbH Christophstraße 15-17 50670 Köln. A/B testing offers analysis of user behavior by showing slightly varied website contents to different user groups, depending on profile matching. Thereby, TeamViewer analysis its online services, improves its web offerings, and can create an interesting user journey. In order for TeamViewer to create such analysis, we use cookies, which are being placed on your computer. Please note that your IP address will be shortened before reports are being created and TeamViewer does not match other information we may receive about you to this abbreviated IP address. You can opt to delete such cookies or even prevent them from being stored on your computer. However, if you choose to either delete such cookies or prevent their installation, please note that you may not be able to use all of our website functionalities. Legal basis for such processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Currently, we use social media plugins (“ **plugins** ”) from **Facebook** , **Google+** , **LinkedIn** and **Twitter** (“ **plugin provider** ”)

TeamViewer uses Facebook plugins on our website which are provided by Facebook Inc. Facebook’s plugins are identifiable by the Facebook logo and/or the “thumbs up” – symbol. TeamViewer also uses the “+1” button from Google Plus on our website, which is operated by Google Inc.; the plugin is identifiable by the “+1” symbol on a white and colored background. Furthermore, TeamViewer uses the ”in” button from LinkedIn, which can be identified by a blue button. Additionally, TeamViewer uses the short messaging service Twitter Inc, which can be identified by a button that contains a bird.

By using plugins, TeamViewer provides an opportunity to interact with social media and other social media users on its website. Plugins are provided to increase TeamViewer’s internet presence and make it more interesting to you. Legal basis for use of the plugins is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

Every time you visit our website and any part thereof that contains a plugin, the plugin causes your browser to directly connect with the plugin provider’s server. With regard to Facebook and its own statement, IP addresses collected within Germany are apparently anonymized right after collection.

By activating the plugin, your personal data as described under **C.** is transmitted to and stored by the plugin provider, likely on a server in the USA. As personal data is collected by and through cookies, we recommend that you delete all cookies through security settings of your browser. Please note that data collection and processing are beyond TeamViewers control and we have neither been informed of the entire scope of data collection, purpose of the processing, nor any data retention periods. We have also not been informed if and when data is being deleted. With regard to Google and according to its own statement, Google stores your browsing history when you activate a “+1” button for a period of up to two weeks for system maintenance and troubleshooting purposes.

Plugin provider store data collected about you as user profiles and use such data for advertisement purposes, market research and/or need based design of their websites. Evaluation of such data (even of users not logged in) is particularly used for need-based advertisements and to notify other users of the same social network of your activities on our website.

You have a right of objection concerning such user profiling, however, you have to address such objection to the respective plugin provider. In order to properly address your demand, we provide you with the relevant addresses:

  *  **Facebook Inc.** , 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>; Additional information on data collection: <https://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084>
  * **Google Inc.** , 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA; for further information on Google’ privacy refer to: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.
  *  **LinkedIn Corporation** , 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; for further information on LinkedIn’s privacy refer to: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=uno-reg-guest-home-privacy-policy> .
  *  **Twitter, Inc.** , 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; for further information on Twitter’s privacy refer to: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>.

Your data is being transmitted to the plugin provider, regardless if you maintain a profile with the plugin provider and/or if you are currently logged in. If you are currently logged into your social media profile, data collected on your visit of our website is directly matched to your social media profile. If you activate the plugin, e.g. by liking or retweeting our website, such information is stored in your social media profile and will be publicly shared with your contacts. We recommend that you log off your social media profile every time you are done using it, particularly, before you activate any plug in buttons so that you can avoid a matching of data with your social media profile.

###  **I. YouTube Videos**

TeamViewer may integrate videos in our website, which are stored on <https://www.youtube.com/>. These videos can be played on our website. When you visit the TeamViewer website, YouTube receives information on what particular website you visit. Your personal data as described under C. is transmitted to YouTube. Such transmission takes place, regardless if you are logged into your YouTube account, or if you do not maintain such account. If you are logged into your YouTube account, your personal data will be matched with your YouTube profile. If you do not wish that your personal data is being matched with your profile, you should log out of your YouTube account prior to activating a YouTube video.

Legal basis for integration of YouTube Videos into our TeamViewer website is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. TeamViewer uses YouTube videos to make our website more interesting to you and to integrate a service with which users may receive useful information about our services.

YouTube stores your data as a user profile and uses your personal data for advertisement, market research and/or need-based design of its website. Evaluation of such personal data is done, even of user who were not logged into YouTube, for need-based advertisement and to inform other YouTube users of your activities on our website.

Please note, that it is beyond TeamViewers control how long and in what way YouTube will retain your data. For further information concerning purpose and scope of data collection and processing, please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

You have a right to object to such processing of your personal data, however, you will have to address such right to YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA.

##  **K. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to use all of the functionalities of our website; where we ask for consent and you choose not to provide it, we may not be able to provide you with the information or service requested.

##  **L. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making. As described under G., H., I. and K., TeamViewer uses your personal data for profiling, unless you changed your browser settings to prevent cookie placements. Evaluation of your personal data by Google Analytics is done after your IP address has been abbreviated so that you can no longer be identified.

##  **M. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [datarequest@teamviewer.com](mailto:datarequest@teamviewer.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data.

Should you have any questions, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

This Policy contains links to sites and information that is not under TeamViewer direct control. These links are therefore subject to change and TeamViewer will review and update this Policy periodically to reflect such changes.

##  **TeamViewer Product Privacy Policy**

 **Introduction**  
We at TeamViewer GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of our TeamViewer product, consisting of the Software as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **TeamViewer** ”).

 **1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**  
A. Controller  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Catagories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

 **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**  
A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

##  **1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**

###  **A. Controller**

TeamViewer GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen, is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act _concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you_. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of the Software as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer.

###  **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer GmbH appointed Mr. Julian Häcker as external data protection officer, who can be reached at dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de or at ENSECUR GmbH, to the attention of Mr. Julian Häcker, Rotebühlplatz 20A, 70173 Stuttgart

###  **C. Categories of Data**

####  **I. Download TeamViewer:**

When you download TeamViewer to your computer, TeamViewer GmbH collects your **IP address and **name****.

####  **II. Signing up for TeamViewer:**

When you sign up for TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH collects your **name, email address, a **password** of your choice, along with **time, date** and **time zone**** of you signing in.

####  **III. License Auditing:**

We will collect information about the **frequency of your use** of the Software and the Server Services.

####  **IV. Feedback:**

When you provide a feedback concerning your TeamViewer experience, TeamViewer GmbH collects your **IP address and your **email address** , if you chose to provide us with therewith. If you attach TeamViewer **log files** or **screen shots**** , TeamViewer GmbH will also collect these.

####  **V. Paid subscription:**

When you use TeamViewer and pay a subscription fee, TeamViewer GmbH additionally collects **information to support payment processing** , which includes a payment token provided by our Payment Service Provider to identify the transaction.

####  **VI. Newsletter:**

If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer GmbH collects your **email address**. TeamViewer GmbH uses the so-called double opt-in method by which you receive a confirmation email after you provided us with your email address. However, please refer to Section D. VI. for paid subscriptions.

####  **VII. Support:**

When you contact our support we will collect your **name, time and **date** of your request and your **email address** if you contacted us via email, otherwise your **telephone number**** if you contacted us via telephone.

###  **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

####  **I. Download TeamViewer:**

When you download TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use TeamViewer. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of TeamViewer, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

####  **II. Signing up for TeamViewer:**

When you sign up to TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

####  **III. License Auditing:**

TeamViewer GmbH is using information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

####  **IV. Feedback:**

If you place an inquiry with TeamViewer by using the in product feedback feature, TeamViewer GmbH needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. IV is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

####  **V. Paid subscription:**

When you use TeamViewer and pay a subscription fee, TeamViewer GmbH additionally collects information to support payment processing, which includes a payment token provided by our Payment Service Provider to identify the transaction. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. IV is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

####  **VI. Newsletter:**

If you sign up for TeamViewer’s newsletter, TeamViewer GmbH processes your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. Legal basis to provide you with the newsletter is your consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may revoke at any time with effect for the future. In case you have a paid subscription, we may use your email address to send you information on similar products and services. Legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR, sec. 7 para. 3 Unfair Competition Act (“ **UWG** “).

####  **VII. Support:**

In case you contact our support, we will process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. VII. Is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

####  **XII. Other:**

Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e) GDPR.

###  **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer GmbH has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

###  **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

TeamViewer GmbH retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer GmbH will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer GmbH is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer.

Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

Personal data provided in connection with TeamViewer’s feedback feature are retained for a period of three (3) months and deleted thereafter.

If you provide us with your email address to receive TeamViewer’s newsletter but do not confirm the confirmation email you received within 24 hours, TeamViewer GmbH will delete your newsletter request.

When you contact our support, we will delete your personal data three (3) months after the request has been resolved.

###  **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

###  **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer GmbH does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

###  **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at privacy@teamviewer.com in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer GmbH in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

##  **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product**

When you use TeamViewer, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with connecting to other devices, initiating meetings, or the hosting of the contacts that you upload. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how TeamViewer works.

###  **A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer**

####  **I.Remote control:**

When you use TeamViewer for remote control purposes, TeamViewer GmbH will receive an **ID and your **IP address**** in addition.

####  **II. Log sessions reporting:**

You may choose to use our log sessions for connection reporting feature which holds **IP address, screen name and **TeamViewer ID****.

####  **III. Profile Picture:**

You may choose to edit your profile and upload a **profile picture** , in which case TeamViewer GmbH will store your profile picture. If you choose to upload a picture of yourself, please bear in mind that such picture is visible to your TeamViewer contacts. Please be aware that pictures may reveal your ethnic origin or health data, or may serve as biometric identifier. Those categories of personal data are considered to be sensitive data, so called special categories of data.

####  **IV. Meeting:**

When you use TeamViewer for meetings, such as presentations, video calls, and phone calls (Voice over IP), TeamViewer GmbH will receive your **meeting ID and **name**. If use TeamViewer’s schedule meeting function, TeamViewer GmbH will receive **subject of a meeting, start** and **end date** and **time, time zone** , and a **password**** , if you chose this option. Please note that TeamViewer offers you the option to share your screen via the presentation, video call or phone call option. When you share your screen, please bear in mind that participants can see all items on your desktop. If you do not want to grant other participants access to your desktop, we recommend that you disable the screen share option under settings > close screen share.

TeamViewer meeting my video enables you to be seen by other participants through your build in device camera. TeamViewer meeting enables you to record your presentations, video and phone calls.

####  **V. Contacts:**

When you save contacts in TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH will receive your contacts. Please be mindful that contacts saved may contain personal data of third parties, which may not be aware that you saved them in TeamViewer.

###  **B. Data Usage**

TeamViewer GmbH is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of TeamViewer as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the End User License Agreement where additional information on security measures is available.

TeamViewer relies upon certain information in order to establish secure remote connections for the device or devices that you use. For each device, this information includes the Machine ID (MID), the Device ID, along with the IP address that is applicable at the start of a connection. The MID includes the MAC address, combined with other device-related information to ensure uniqueness. It is a unique identifier that allows TeamViewer master infrastructure to generate the TeamViewer Device ID and allows it to distinguish between unique user devices that have the TeamViewer products installed.

The MID, Device ID and IP address will be retained for a period of three (3) months following the end of the contractual relationship with you.

Please note that if you upload a profile picture to your TeamViewer profile, TeamViewer GmbH will retain your profile picture for as long as you are a user, unless and until you replace your profile picture. TeamViewer GmbH will not retain any copies of your profile picture.

We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

###  **C. Data Subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

Summary of Changes

Date| Description of Change  
---|---  
6th August 2018| Clause 2.B Data Usage: Additional information provided to describe the use of the TeamViewer Machine ID, Device ID and MAC address.

Clause I Your rights: Update to provide consistency of contact email address.  
  
##  **TeamViewer IoT Product Privacy Policy**

 **Introduction**  
We at TeamViewer GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of IoT, consisting of the TeamViewer IoT Monitoring and TeamViewer IoT Remote Control as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **IoT** “).

 **1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**  
A. Controller respectively Provider  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

 **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of IoT**  
A. Personal Data processed through your use of IoT  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

##  **1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer**

###  **A. Controller respectively Provider**

TeamViewer GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen (“ **TeamViewer”), is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR**** ”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act _concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you_. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of IoT as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer.

###  **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mr. Julian Häcker as external data protection officer, who can be reached at [dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de](mailto:dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de) or at ENSECUR GmbH, to the attention of Mr. Julian Häcker, Rotebühlplatz 20A, 70173 Stuttgart.

###  **C. Categories of Data**

 **I. Download IoT: When you download IoT to your computer, TeamViewer collects your **IP address** and **name****.

 **II. Sign Up: Your **full name, address, user name, password, email address, time, date, time zone** and **bank information**** when you first sign up to use IoT, and in particular your email address for IoT to provide you with notifications and alerts.

 **III. Protocol and Usage Data: We collect personal data transmitted through your browser, such as your **IP address** , **date** and **time of request** , **time zone differences** to Greenwhich Mean Time (GMT), **content of request** (specific site), **access status / HTTP status code, volume of data transmitted each time, website from which the request comes, browser, operating system** and its interface, **language and version of browser software, user’s country of origin**. Additionally, we processes your **user name** and **password**** , which are linked to your user profile. We collect information about your use of IoT.

 **IV. License Auditing: We will collect information about the **frequency of your use**** of IoT and the Server Services.

###  **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

 **I. Download:** When you download IoT, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use IoT. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of IoT, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **II. Signing up for TeamViewer:** When you sign up to IoT, TeamViewer uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

 **III. Protocol and Usage Data:** When you log into TeamViewer IoT, we process your personal data so that a log in is successful and you do not encounter technical problems. We may process the usage data to improve functionalities of our IoT service. Legal basis for such processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

 **IV. License Auditing:** TeamViewer is using information about the frequency of your use of IoT in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

###  **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

In the context of the provision of IoT, employees of TeamViewer’s affiliate Monitis LLC, located in Armenia (address: 9 Alek Manukyan St, Yerevan 0070, Armenia), may also have access to certain metadata and to data about the usage of the TeamViewer IoT for the purpose of performing analysis to improve and develop the TeamViewer IoT. Furthermore, employees from Monitis LLC may, in limited cases, provide you with support and thus receive access to your personal data. Additionally, employees of Hotjar Ltd, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, may receive your personal data to analyze user behavior of IoT users.

###  **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer. Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

###  **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

###  **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

###  **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

##  **2\. Information concerning your responsible use of IoT**

When you use IoT, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with the use of the platform for your IoT decives. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how IoT works.

###  **A. Personal Data processed through your use of IoT**

When you use IoT, we receive information such as the **amount of devices connected through IoT, **log in time and date, functionalities used** and **metrics**** entered while you use IoT. Depending on the metrics defined by you in the IoT (the so-called metadata), we also receive data from devices that you connect with IoT (e.g. the temperature of a device or other metrics, as defined by you). While generally such kind of data in and of itself typically includes no personal data, we cannot exclude that you collect information that – either in itself or in connection with additional information – may be linked to individual persons (e.g. maintenance staff for an IoT device). It is therefore your responsibility to ensure that data collection through your IoT devices is fair, transparent and in line with applicable data protection laws.

###  **B. Data Usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of IoT as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the End User License Agreement where additional information on security measures is available. To improve IoT’s functionalities, TeamViewer uses Hotjar to assist with the diagnosis of technical problems and to analyze user behavior trends. Hotjar is a software as a service tracking tool offered by Hotjar limited, Level 2, St. Julian’s Business Center, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians, Malta. Hotjar is only activated from time to time, mostly when updates are released. Hotjar collects information about the device that is used to log in to the TeamViewer IoT, such as the device’s IP address (captured and stored in an anonymized format); device screen resolution; device type (unique device identifiers), operating system, and browser type, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display the Hotjar enabled site, mouse events (movements, location and clicks), keypressers, referring URL and domain, pages visited, geographic location (country only), date and time of access. The sole purpose of collecting this data is to improve the functionality of IoT. TeamViewer does not store the data collected through Hotjar for longer than 24 hours and masks the user’s private information. The user can object to the use of Hotjar here: <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out/> and can learn about Hotjar’s ability to use and share information through the Hotjar Terms & Conditions of Use, available at <https://www.hotjar.com/terms/>, and the Hotjar Privacy Policy, available at <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy/>.

We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

###  **C. Data Subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

##  **TeamViewer Cookie Policy**

###  **I. Introduction**

TeamViewer strives to be clear and transparent about any data (anonymous or otherwise) that we collect about you online. As described in Section C. I. of our Privacy Policy, we use cookies to ensure the best possible user experience of our website. In this policy we elaborate how we use cookies, their business purpose and how this allows us to improve our service. It also tells you how you can manage the cookies that are stored on your device.

When you visit our websites (through any device), you agree the application of this Cookies Policy in addition to any other terms and conditions which may apply.

TeamViewer reserves the right to make any changes to this Cookie Policy. Any such changes shall be updated here or in our Privacy Policy and we will inform you through our cookie banner. We assume that you agree to any such changes by your continued use of our websites.

###  **II. What are cookies?**

Cookies are small files containing information related to your internet settings, which are downloaded by your browser to the device you use when you visit our website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website (first-party cookies) on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie (third-party cookies). Cookies perform a variety of useful jobs, such as remembering your preferences, adapting the content that you see and improving your online experience.

###  **III. When does TeamViewer place cookies?**

TeamViewer uses cookies on our website (such as teamviewer.com, Blizz.com, ITbrain.com, and TeamViewerIOT.com) and mobile applications. Any browser visiting these website will receive cookies from us.

###  **IV. What types of cookies are being used?**

TeamViewer uses both first party and third-party cookies, for example necessary as well as performance and marketing cookies. First party cookies are those set by TeamViewer. All other cookies are third party cookies, from companies such as Google Analytics, Hotjar, Facebook, Hubspot, Pubmatic, Baidu, Optimizely, LinkedIn, Ad Roll etc . In some cases, the information derived from these cookies may allow us to associate information with an identifiable individual. Further information on different cookie types is provided below. Please refer to the full list of cookies that TeamViewer uses for more information in Annex 1.:

  * Session Cookies

Session cookies last only for the duration of your visit of our website and are deleted when you close your browser. These help us to identify that a user of a particular device is navigating from page to page, supporting website security or basic functionality.

Many of the cookies we use are session cookies. For example, they help us to identify the average time you spend on our website. CMDD – This cookie would identify the user for our programmatic ads – CasaleMedia is an ad exchange network.

  * Persistent cookies

Persistent cookies continue to exist even after you have closed your browser, and allow a website to remember your actions and preferences, particularly remember you as an existing user. Sometimes persistent cookies are used by websites to provide targeted advertising based upon the browsing history of the device.

TeamViewer uses persistent cookies in a few ways, for example, _ga- Google Analytics cookie registers a unique ID used to distinguish users.

Both session as well as persistent cookies can serve different purposes and may be placed either by TeamViewer or by a third party:

  * Strictly necessary cookies

These cookies are essential in order to enable us to provide you with certain features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for such as a registered visitor cookie (unique identifier provided to each registered user to recognize them throughout the visit and when they return) and webshop related services, cannot be provided. These cookies are not implemented to gather information about you for the purposes of marketing. Please refer to the full list of cookies that TeamViewer uses for more information in Annex 1.

  * Performance cookies

These cookies are used to collect information about the performance of our website and your visit and use of our website. For example, the number of visitors that used our website and the pages that are popular among users. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor although they may collect the IP address of the device used to access the site. Such information is collect anonymously and is solely used for the purpose of improving our website and the user experience. By using our websites, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device, however you can block these cookies using your browser settings.

  * Functionality cookies

These cookies allow TeamViewer’s website to remember your preferences, such as your username, language settings, and/or the region you are in. The information these cookies collect is anonymized (i.e. it does not contain your name, address etc.) and they do not track your browsing activity across other websites. By using our websites, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device, however you can block these cookies using your browser settings.

  * Marketing cookies

These cookies collect several pieces of information about your browsing habits. They are usually placed by advertising networks. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organizations such as media publishers. These organizations do this in order to provide you with targeted adverts more relevant to you and your interests. This type of advertising is called online behavioral advertising and place an icon in the top right-hand corner of an advert. This icon when clicked, will take you through to the website Your Online Choices where there is more help and guidance for you to Opt-out of this type of advertising. By using our websites, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.

  * Unclassified cookies

These are cookies that we are in the process of classifying, together with the providers of individual cookies.

###  **V. Tracking in our emails**

Just like the cookies we use on our websites, TeamViewer uses cookies and similar technologies, such as beacons, pixels, and tags, in some emails. This is for example the case when you receive an email from us: TeamViewer will know whether you open, read, or delete the message. If you click on a link provided to you in a marketing email, TeamViewer will use a cookie to receive information on what pages you visit, what content you download, and whether you are a signed into one of our products. Web beacons for example, which are small invisible images placed in emails, will tell us if you’ve opened the email and read it, which email software and web browser you use, which device you use and your IP address. We also use web beacons to help us display emails in the best format for your device. Sometimes TeamViewer may use advance technologies like Link tracking. These functions based on the number of hyperlinks, each of which has a unique tag. When you click on one of these links the mailing company logs the click so that we can understand who has clicked through from an email to our website. We use this information to tailor future messages to you.

####  **What to do when you do not want to accept cookies or want them removed?**

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by any website – including those from TeamViewer or its affiliate websites, you should do this through the web browser settings for each web browser you use, on each device you use to access the Internet.

Here some information browser manufacturers provide to help manage your cookies. Please see below for more information:

  * <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (link for Google Chrome)
  * <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/260971/description-of-cookies> (internet explorer)
  * <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer> (mozilla firefox)
  * <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042?locale=en_US> (safari for mac)
  * <https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265> (safari mobile)
  * [https://support.google.com/nexus/answer/54068?visit_id=0-636620904019897372-3345341377&hl=en&rd=1](https://support.google.com/nexus/answer/54068?visit_id=0-636620904019897372-3345341377&hl=en&rd=1) (android)
  * <https://www.opera.com/help> (opera)
  * <https://www.opera.com/help/mobile/android#privacy> (opera mobile)

Please be aware that some of our services, for example, the online web shop portal will not function if your web browser does not accept cookies. You may wish to visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and/or <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> which contains comprehensive information on how to choose and accept cookies on a wider variety of browsers. If you wish not to accept cookies from TeamViewer emails, just close the email before downloading any images or clicking on any links. You can also set your browser to restrict or reject cookies. These settings will apply to all cookies on websites and emails. In some instances, depending on your email or browser settings, cookies in an email may be automatically accepted (for example, when you’ve added an email address to your address book or safe senders list). Please check your email browser or device instructions for more information on this.

####  **How to control and delete cookies**

If you want to restrict or block the cookies we set, you can do this through your browser settings. The ‘help’ function within your browser should tell you how.

Alternatively, you could visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information on cookies on a wide variety of browsers. You’ll also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer. To learn about controlling cookies on the browser of your mobile device please refer to your handset manual.

####  **Supplementary information**

We may embed external content from third party websites (e.g. Facebook, YouTube) within our website periodically. In addition to this, we sometimes partner with third parties who provide services for us which you can navigate to from our website. These third parties may use cookies, you can find out about their approach to cookies on their websites.

####  **ANNEXE 1**

Here is the full list of cookies that TeamViewer uses:

Cookies for **teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
__cfduid| hs-analytics.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hsforms.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hs-scripts.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hubspot.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
CookieConsent| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
end_user_id| log.optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
end_user_id| optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics|   
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
optimizelyBuckets| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Stores settings on Optimizely user experience experiments and variations that the visitor has been bucketed into. This ensures the visitor consistently sees the same variation  
optimizelyEndUserId| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
optimizelySegments| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used by Optimizely to store the user’s audience and dimension information (e.g.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
__hstc| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
hubspotutk| teamviewer.com| 10 years| Marketing| Keeps track of a visitor’s identity. This cookie is passed to the marketing platform HubSpot on form submission and used when de-duplicating contacts.  
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
PageVisitCommercialScore| teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
uslk_e| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Unclassified|   
tv_wsp_i| wsp.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **blog.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| blog.teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
PHPSESSID| blog.teamviewer.com| Session| Necessary| Preserves user session state across page requests.  
__cfduid| hs-analytics.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hs-scripts.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hubspot.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
f5_cspm| pubmatic.com| Session| Necessary| Saves the address and port number of the web server that is managing the session. Used to improve the website’s performance security.  
lang| ads.linkedin.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
uid| videostat.com| 29 days| Preferences| Unique user ID that recognizes the user on returning visits  
@@History/@@scroll|#| blog.teamviewer.com| Persistent| Statistics|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gat| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
xuid| 3lift.com| Session| Marketing|   
auid| acuityplatform.com| 68 years| Marketing| Registers a unique user ID that recognises the user’s browser when visiting websites that show ads from the same ad network. The cookie is used to collect statistical data of the visitor’s movements and to generate targeted ads.  
ADGRX_CM_LIVERAMP_BRIDGED| adgrx.com| Session| Marketing|   
ADGRX_UID| adgrx.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
_adlTrac_| adlucent.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
tuuid| admedo.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
tuuid_last_update| admedo.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
aoc| areyouahuman.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
ul_cb/sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
__ar_v4| blog.teamviewer.com| 2083 days| Marketing| Optimises ad display based on the user’s movement combined and various advertiser bids for displaying user ads.  
_te_| blog.teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
CMDD| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMSC| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMST| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rum| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing|   
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
demdex| demdex.net| 179 days| Marketing| Via a unique ID that is used for semantic content analysis  
dpm| demdex.net| 179 days| Marketing|   
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
test_cookie| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing| Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies.  
er_guid| eyereturn.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
__ev_uid| eyeviewads.com| 6 years| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits. Used for conversion tracking and to measure the efficacy of online ads.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
ra1_uid| gwallet.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
__ptq.gif| hubspot.com| Session| Marketing| Sends data to the marketing platform Hubspot about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
uuid| innovid.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
lidc| linkedin.com| Session| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
w/1.0/sd| openx.net| Session| Marketing|   
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
did| pippio.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
didts| pippio.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
nnls| pippio.com| 2 months| Marketing|   
pxrc| pippio.com| 2 months| Marketing|   
pa_#_ts| prfct.co| 2 years| Marketing| Used across websites that use the same ad network to display ads to the other advertisers in the network.  
pa_uid| prfct.co| 2 years| Marketing| Used across websites that use the same ad network to display ads to the other advertisers in the network.  
anProfile| pro-market.net| 179 days| Marketing|   
KRTBCOOKIE_#| pubmatic.com| 399 days| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
#.gif| rlcdn.com| Session| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
pxrc| rlcdn.com| 2 months| Marketing|   
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
tap.php| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
__hssc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hssrc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hstc| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
hubspotutk| teamviewer.com| 10 years| Marketing| Keeps track of a visitor’s identity. This cookie is passed to the marketing platform HubSpot on form submission and used when de-duplicating contacts.  
sync-his| tidaltv.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
tidal_ttid| tidaltv.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers the ads provided by Videology that the user has seen and/or clicked. Used to generate a demographic profile of the user.  
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
id| videostat.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
GPS| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.  
PREF| youtube.com| 8 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE| youtube.com| 179 days| Marketing| Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.  
YSC| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.  
PageVisitCommercialScore| blog.teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
tvUserIDd| blog.teamviewer.com| 1 day| Unclassified|   
cm/b/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/l/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/o/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/u/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
avlcnt| dc.arrivalist.com| 5 years| Unclassified|   
avlukey| dc.arrivalist.com| 5 years| Unclassified|   
cs| s-cs.send.microad.jp| Session| Unclassified|   
sv_sid| securedvisit.com| 3 years| Unclassified|   
sv_sid_src| securedvisit.com| 3 years| Unclassified|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
sskya| sundaysky.com| 6 days| Unclassified|   
sskyCreationTime| sundaysky.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
sskyu| sundaysky.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
i/adsct| t.co| Session| Unclassified|   
mat_ep| teamviewer.com| 29 days| Unclassified|   
mat_tel| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **channelpartner.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
BIGipServer#| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| Session| Necessary| Used to distribute traffic to the website on several servers in order to optimise response times.  
CookieConsent| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
TS#| | | Unclassified|   
JSESSIONID| nr-data.net| Session| Necessary| Preserves users states across page requests.  
BIGipServer#| rv.treehousei.com| Session| Necessary| Used to distribute traffic to the website on several servers in order to optimise response times.  
TS#| | | Unclassified|   
__utma| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Collects data on the number of times a user has visited the website as well as dates for the first and most recent visit. Used by Google Analytics.  
__utmb| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user accessed the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.  
__utmc| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user leaves the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.  
__utmt| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used to throttle the speed of requests to the server.  
__utmz| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| 6 months| Statistics| Collects data on where the user came from  
__utm.gif| google-analytics.com| Session| Statistics| Google Analytics Tracking Code that logs details about the visitor’s browser and computer.  
PPCsrf| channelpartner.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **community.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| community.teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
f5_cspm| pubmatic.com| Session| Necessary| Saves the address and port number of the web server that is managing the session. Used to improve the website’s performance security.  
lang| ads.linkedin.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
lang| login.teamviewer.com| 6 days| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
@@History/@@scroll|#| community.teamviewer.com| Persistent| Statistics|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gat| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
xuid| 3lift.com| Session| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
ul_cb/sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
CMDD| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMSC| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMST| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rum| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing|   
__ar_v4| community.teamviewer.com| 2083 days| Marketing| Optimises ad display based on the user’s movement combined and various advertiser bids for displaying user ads.  
_hjIncludedInSample| community.teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Determines if the user’s navigation should be registered in a certain statistical place holder.  
_te_| community.teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
LiSESSIONID| community.teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Preserves users states across page requests.  
LithiumVisitor| community.teamviewer.com| 10 years| Marketing| Preserves users states across page requests.  
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
test_cookie| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing| Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
LiSESSIONID| kaymo75663.i.lithium.com| Session| Marketing| Preserves users states across page requests.  
LithiumVisitor| kaymo75663.i.lithium.com| 10 years| Marketing| Preserves users states across page requests.  
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
lidc| linkedin.com| Session| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
w/1.0/sd| openx.net| Session| Marketing|   
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
KRTBCOOKIE_#| pubmatic.com| 399 days| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
#.gif| rlcdn.com| Session| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
tap.php| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
PageVisitCommercialScore| community.teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
tvUserIDd| community.teamviewer.com| 1 day| Unclassified|   
ValueSurveyVisitorCount| community.teamviewer.com| 10 years| Unclassified|   
VISITOR_BEACON| community.teamviewer.com| 10 years| Unclassified|   
cm/b/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/l/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/o/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/u/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
__xFlUD3rsEr4sd| login.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
BrowserAuthToken| login.teamviewer.com| 2915224 days| Unclassified|   
LogoutUserAfterAction| login.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
TVConsoleCookieSupport| login.teamviewer.com| 2915224 days| Unclassified|   
cs| s-cs.send.microad.jp| Session| Unclassified|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
i/adsct| t.co| Session| Unclassified|   
mat_ep| teamviewer.com| 29 days| Unclassified|   
mat_tel| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
tv_wsp_i| wsp.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **content.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
__cfduid| hs-analytics.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hsforms.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hs-scripts.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hubspot.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
f5_cspm| pubmatic.com| Session| Necessary| Saves the address and port number of the web server that is managing the session. Used to improve the website’s performance security.  
ASP.NET_SessionId| teamviewer.com| Session| Necessary| Preserves the visitor’s session state across page requests.  
CookieConsent| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
lang| ads.linkedin.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
bucket_map| log.optimizely.com| 10 years| Preferences| Stores settings on Optimizely user experience experiments and variations that the visitor has been bucketed into. This ensures the visitor consistently sees the same variation  
lang| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 6 days| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
end_user_id| log.optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
bucket_map| optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics|   
end_user_id| optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics|   
@@History/@@scroll|#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gat| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
optimizelyBuckets| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Stores settings on Optimizely user experience experiments and variations that the visitor has been bucketed into. This ensures the visitor consistently sees the same variation  
optimizelyEndUserId| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
optimizelyPendingLogEvents| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Optimizely as a cache of a user’s actions between tracking calls.  
optimizelySegments| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used by Optimizely to store the user’s audience and dimension information (e.g.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
xuid| 3lift.com| Session| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
ul_cb/sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
CMDD| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMSC| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMST| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rum| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing|   
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
test_cookie| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing| Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
__ptq.gif| hubspot.com| Session| Marketing| Sends data to the marketing platform Hubspot about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
lidc| linkedin.com| Session| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
w/1.0/sd| openx.net| Session| Marketing|   
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
KRTBCOOKIE_#| pubmatic.com| 399 days| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
#.gif| rlcdn.com| Session| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
tap.php| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
__ar_v4| teamviewer.com| 2083 days| Marketing| Optimises ad display based on the user’s movement combined and various advertiser bids for displaying user ads.  
__hssc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hssrc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hstc| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
_te_| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
hubspotutk| teamviewer.com| 10 years| Marketing| Keeps track of a visitor’s identity. This cookie is passed to the marketing platform HubSpot on form submission and used when de-duplicating contacts.  
optimizely_data$$#$$asyncInfo| teamviewer.com| | Unclassified|   
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
api/chat/slot/user| api.userlike.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/b/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/l/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/o/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/u/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
__xFlUD3rsEr4sd| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
BrowserAuthToken| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
LogoutUserAfterAction| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
TVConsoleCookieSupport| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
cs| s-cs.send.microad.jp| Session| Unclassified|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
i/adsct| t.co| Session| Unclassified|   
_uslk_test| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
PageVisitCommercialScore| teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
sdPuqGtW9arY0QIG8N7sDVCbqLPXXjtZxY6IKhN2kPU| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
tvUserIDd| teamviewer.com| 1 day| Unclassified|   
uslk_e| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Unclassified|   
uslk_s| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
t/mco| wsp.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
tv_wsp_i| wsp.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **jobs.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| jobs.teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
PHPSESSID| jobs.teamviewer.com| Session| Necessary| Preserves user session state across page requests.  
f5_cspm| pubmatic.com| Session| Necessary| Saves the address and port number of the web server that is managing the session. Used to improve the website’s performance security.  
lang| ads.linkedin.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
__utm.gif| google-analytics.com| Session| Statistics| Google Analytics Tracking Code that logs details about the visitor’s browser and computer.  
__utma| jobs.jobvite.com| 2 years| Statistics| Collects data on the number of times a user has visited the website as well as dates for the first and most recent visit. Used by Google Analytics.  
__utmb| jobs.jobvite.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user accessed the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.  
__utmc| jobs.jobvite.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a timestamp with the exact time of when the user leaves the website. Used by Google Analytics to calculate the duration of a website visit.  
__utmt| jobs.jobvite.com| Session| Statistics| Used to throttle the speed of requests to the server.  
__utmv| jobs.jobvite.com| 2 years| Statistics| Saves user-defined tracking parameters for use in Google Analytics.  
__utmz| jobs.jobvite.com| 6 months| Statistics| Collects data on where the user came from  
@@History/@@scroll|#| jobs.teamviewer.com| | Unclassified|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gat| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
xuid| 3lift.com| Session| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
ul_cb/sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
CMDD| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMSC| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMST| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rum| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing|   
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
test_cookie| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing| Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
NID| google.com| 6 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
__ar_v4| jobs.teamviewer.com| 2083 days| Marketing| Optimises ad display based on the user’s movement combined and various advertiser bids for displaying user ads.  
_te_| jobs.teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
lidc| linkedin.com| Session| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
w/1.0/sd| openx.net| Session| Marketing|   
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
KRTBCOOKIE_#| pubmatic.com| 399 days| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
#.gif| rlcdn.com| Session| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
tap.php| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
cm/b/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/l/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/o/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/u/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
ADRUM_69_0_0| jobs.jobvite.com| Session| Unclassified|   
PageVisitCommercialScore| jobs.teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
tvUserIDd| jobs.teamviewer.com| 1 day| Unclassified|   
guestidc| jobvite.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cs| s-cs.send.microad.jp| Session| Unclassified|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
i/adsct| t.co| Session| Unclassified|   
mat_ep| teamviewer.com| 29 days| Unclassified|   
mat_tel| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **login.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| login.teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
lang| login.teamviewer.com| 6 days| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
__xFlUD3rsEr4sd| login.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
BrowserAuthToken| login.teamviewer.com| 2915224 days| Unclassified|   
TVConsoleCookieSupport| login.teamviewer.com| 2915224 days| Unclassified|   
tv_wsp_i| wsp.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Cookies for **pages.teamviewer.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
__cfduid| hs-analytics.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hsforms.net| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hs-scripts.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
__cfduid| hubspot.com| 1 year| Necessary| Used by the content network  
f5_cspm| pubmatic.com| Session| Necessary| Saves the address and port number of the web server that is managing the session. Used to improve the website’s performance security.  
ASP.NET_SessionId| teamviewer.com| Session| Necessary| Preserves the visitor’s session state across page requests.  
CookieConsent| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
lang| ads.linkedin.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
lang| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 6 days| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
end_user_id| log.optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
end_user_id| optimizely.com| 10 years| Statistics|   
@@History/@@scroll|#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gat| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
optimizelyBuckets| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Stores settings on Optimizely user experience experiments and variations that the visitor has been bucketed into. This ensures the visitor consistently sees the same variation  
optimizelyEndUserId| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used to measure how selected users react to targeted changes to the website’s content and functionality  
optimizelyPendingLogEvents| teamviewer.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Optimizely as a cache of a user’s actions between tracking calls.  
optimizelySegments| teamviewer.com| 179 days| Statistics| Used by Optimizely to store the user’s audience and dimension information (e.g.  
tluid| 3lift.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
xuid| 3lift.com| Session| Marketing|   
BizoID| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
UserMatchHistory| ads.linkedin.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Regulates synchronisation of user identification and exchange of user data between various ad services.  
tuuid| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers whether or not the user has consented to the use of cookies.  
tuuid_lu| bidswitch.net| 1 year| Marketing|   
ul_cb/sync| bidswitch.net| Session| Marketing|   
CMDD| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMID| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMPRO| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
CMPS| casalemedia.com| 3 months| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMRUM3| casalemedia.com| 1 year| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMSC| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
CMST| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rum| casalemedia.com| Session| Marketing|   
__adroll| d.adroll.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
IDE| doubleclick.net| 1 year| Marketing| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user’s actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser’s ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
test_cookie| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing| Used to check if the user’s browser supports cookies.  
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
__ptq.gif| hubspot.com| Session| Marketing| Sends data to the marketing platform Hubspot about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
bcookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
bscookie| linkedin.com| 2 years| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
lidc| linkedin.com| Session| Marketing| Used by the social networking service  
i| openx.net| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
w/1.0/sd| openx.net| Session| Marketing|   
adrl| outbrain.com| 3 months| Marketing|   
KRTBCOOKIE_#| pubmatic.com| 399 days| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PUBMDCID| pubmatic.com| 3 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies the user’s device during return visits across websites that use the same ad network. The ID is used to allow targeted ads.  
PugT| pubmatic.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
#.gif| rlcdn.com| Session| Marketing|   
ck1| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rlas3| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing| Collects anonymous data related to the user’s visits to the website  
rtn1-z| rlcdn.com| 179 days| Marketing|   
c| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
khaos| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
put_#| rubiconproject.com| 1 year| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpb| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing| Registers anonymised user data  
rpx| rubiconproject.com| 29 days| Marketing|   
tap.php| rubiconproject.com| Session| Marketing|   
t_gid| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
taboola_usg| taboola.com| 1 year| Marketing|   
__ar_v4| teamviewer.com| 2083 days| Marketing| Optimises ad display based on the user’s movement combined and various advertiser bids for displaying user ads.  
__hssc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hssrc| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
__hstc| teamviewer.com| 2 years| Marketing| Collects anonymous statistical data related to the user’s website visits  
_te_| teamviewer.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that identifies a returning user’s device. The ID is used for targeted ads.  
hubspotutk| teamviewer.com| 10 years| Marketing| Keeps track of a visitor’s identity. This cookie is passed to the marketing platform HubSpot on form submission and used when de-duplicating contacts.  
optimizely_data$$#$$asyncInfo| teamviewer.com| | Unclassified|   
personalization_id| twitter.com| 2 years| Marketing|   
api/chat/slot/user| api.userlike.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/b/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/l/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/o/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
cm/u/out| d.adroll.com| Session| Unclassified|   
__xFlUD3rsEr4sd| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
BrowserAuthToken| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
LogoutUserAfterAction| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
TVConsoleCookieSupport| login-webshop.teamviewer.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
cs| s-cs.send.microad.jp| Session| Unclassified|   
TR| send.microad.jp| 3 months| Unclassified|   
i/adsct| t.co| Session| Unclassified|   
_uslk_test| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
PageVisitCommercialScore| teamviewer.com| 3 months| Unclassified|   
sdPuqGtW9arY0QIG8N7sDVCbqLPXXjtZxY6IKhN2kPU| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
tvUserIDd| teamviewer.com| 1 day| Unclassified|   
uslk_e| teamviewer.com| 1 year| Unclassified|   
uslk_s| teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
t/mco| wsp.teamviewer.com| Session| Unclassified|   
tv_wsp_i| wsp.teamviewer.com| 2 years| Unclassified|   
  
Here is the full list of cookies that ITbrain uses:

Cookies for **itbrain.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId| itbrain.com| Session| Necessary| Preserves the visitor’s session state across page requests.  
CookieConsent| itbrain.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
[SessionID#27]| paypal.com| Session| Necessary|   
@@History/@@scroll|#| itbrain.com| Persistent| Statistics|   
_dc_gtm_UA-#| itbrain.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Tag Manager to control the loading of a Google Analytics script tag.  
_ga| itbrain.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gali| itbrain.com| Session| Statistics|   
_gid| itbrain.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
ads/ga-audiences| google.com| Session| Marketing| Used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors that are likely to convert to customers based on the visitor’s online behaviour across websites.  
collect| google-analytics.com| Session| Marketing| Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.  
GPS| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.  
PREF| youtube.com| 8 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE| youtube.com| 179 days| Marketing| Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.  
YSC| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.  
api/chat/slot/user| api.userlike.com| Session| Unclassified|   
_uslk_test| itbrain.com| Session| Unclassified|   
persistenceID_ItbrainCom| itbrain.com| Session| Unclassified|   
sdPuqGtW9arY0QIG8N7sDVCbqLPXXjtZxY6IKhN2kPU| itbrain.com| Session| Unclassified|   
uslk_e| itbrain.com| 1 year| Unclassified|   
uslk_s| itbrain.com| Session| Unclassified|   
akavpau_ppsd| paypal.com| Session| Unclassified|   
  
Here is the full list of cookies that Blizz uses:

Cookies for **blizz.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| blizz.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
lang| twitter.com| Session| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
_ga| blizz.com| 2 years| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_gat| blizz.com| Session| Statistics| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate  
_gid| blizz.com| Session| Statistics| Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.  
_hjIncludedInSample| blizz.com| Session| Marketing| Determines if the user’s navigation should be registered in a certain statistical place holder.  
r/collect| doubleclick.net| Session| Marketing|   
fr| facebook.com| 3 months| Marketing| Used by Facebook to deliver a series of advertisement products such as real time bidding from third party advertisers.  
tr| facebook.com| Session| Marketing|   
GPS| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.  
PREF| youtube.com| 8 months| Marketing| Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE| youtube.com| 179 days| Marketing| Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.  
YSC| youtube.com| Session| Marketing| Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.  
  
Cookies for **go.blizz.com** :

Name| Provider| ExpireDescription| Category| PurposeDescription  
---|---|---|---|---  
CookieConsent| go.blizz.com| 1 year| Necessary| Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domain  
lang| go.blizz.com| 6 days| Preferences| Remembers the user’s selected language version of a website  
_Dg43tiadlZ56kizt| go.blizz.com| Session| Unclassified|   
BrowserAuthToken| go.blizz.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
isBlizzWebClientAvailableInCountry| go.blizz.com| Session| Unclassified|   
TVConsoleCookieSupport| go.blizz.com| 2915223 days| Unclassified|   
  
## TeamViewer Apps Privacy Policy

## Introduction

We at TeamViewer GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of our TeamViewer product, consisting of the Software as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “TeamViewer”).

Below we provide information about the collection of personal data when using one of the following TeamViewer Apps: TeamViewer Host, TeamViewer QuickSupport and TeamViewer for Remote Control, TeamViewer Pilot, TeamViewer Meeting, Blizz (each referred to hereinafter as “App”).

### 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

A. Controller  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

### 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product

A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

## 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

### A. Controller

TeamViewer GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen, is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of the Software as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer.

### B. Data Protection Officer

TeamViewer GmbH appointed Mr. Julian Häcker as external data protection officer, who can be reached at dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de or at ENSECUR GmbH, to the attention of Mr. Julian Häcker, Rotebühlplatz 20A, 70173 Stuttgart.

### C. Categories of Data

I. Download TeamViewer: By choosing to download our App from an App store, necessary personal data are provided to the app store. This particularly concerns your name/user name, email address, an ID assigned to your app store account, time of the download and your device ID. The processing of your data through the operator of the App store is beyond TeamViewer’s control and we are not responsible for such processing. TeamViewer processes such personal data only insofar as it is necessary for the download to your mobile device.

In addition to the aforementioned personal data sets, TeamViewer also requires information about your device in order to generate a unique Device ID. The specific information used will depend on the type of device and the platform operating system, but may include the device type, device name, the IMEI, the MAC address and the mobile/cell phone number.

II. Signing up for TeamViewer: When you sign up for TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH collects your name, email address, a password of your choice, along with time, date and time zone of you signing in.

III. License Auditing: We will collect information about the frequency of your use of the Software and the Server Services.

IV. Feedback: When you provide a feedback concerning your TeamViewer experience, TeamViewer GmbH collects your IP address and your email address, if you chose to provide us with therewith. If you attach TeamViewer log files or screen shots, TeamViewer GmbH will also collect these.

V. Newsletter: If you sign up for our newsletter, TeamViewer GmbH collects your email address. TeamViewer GmbH uses the so-called double opt-in method by which you receive a confirmation email after you provided us with your email address.

VI. Support: When you contact our support we will collect your name, time and date of your request and your email address if you contacted us via email, otherwise your telephone number if you contacted us via telephone.

### D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing

I. Download: When you download TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use TeamViewer. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of TeamViewer, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

II. Signing up for TeamViewer: When you sign up to TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

III. License Auditing: TeamViewer GmbH is using information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

IV. Feedback: If you place an inquiry with TeamViewer by using the in product feedback feature, TeamViewer GmbH needs to process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. IV is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

V. Newsletter: If you sign up for TeamViewer’s newsletter, TeamViewer GmbH processes your personal data in order to send you the newsletter. Legal basis to provide you with the newsletter is your consent according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a) GDPR, which you may revoke at any time with effect for the future. In case you have a paid subscription, we may use your email address to send you information on similar products and services. Legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR, sec. 7 para. 3 Unfair Competition Act (“UWG”).

VI. Support: In case you contact our support, we will process your personal data in order to answer your request. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. VII. Is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

VII. Other: Where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to, we process your personal data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e) GDPR.

### E. Recipients

TeamViewer GmbH has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third-party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

### F. Retention Periods for Personal Data

TeamViewer GmbH retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer GmbH will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer GmbH is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer.

Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

Personal data provided in connection with TeamViewer’s feedback feature are retained for a period of three (3) months and deleted thereafter.

If you provide us with your email address to receive TeamViewer’s newsletter but do not confirm the confirmation email you received within 24 hours, TeamViewer GmbH will delete your newsletter request.

When you contact our support, we will delete your personal data three (3) months after the request has been resolved.

### G. Statutory/contractual requirement

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

### H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling

TeamViewer GmbH does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

### I. Your Rights

You may contact us either in writing or by email at [datarequest@teamviewer.com](mailto:datarequest@teamviewer.com) in order to exercise the following rights to the extent you are entitled to so under applicable law:

You may access your personal data to check and review such data;  
You may request a copy of your personal data;  
You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;  
You may object to the processing of your personal data;  
You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer GmbH in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

## 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of the Product

When you use TeamViewer, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with connecting to other devices, initiating meetings, or the hosting of the contacts that you upload. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how TeamViewer works.

### A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer

I. Remote control: When you use TeamViewer for remote control purposes, TeamViewer GmbH will receive an ID and your IP address in addition.

II. Log sessions reporting: You may choose to use our log sessions for connection reporting feature which holds IP address, device name, display name and TeamViewer ID.

III. Profile Picture: You may choose to edit your profile and upload a profile picture, in which case TeamViewer GmbH will store your profile picture. If you choose to upload a picture of yourself, please bear in mind that such picture is visible to your TeamViewer contacts. Please be aware that pictures may reveal your ethnic origin or health data, or may serve as a biometric identifier. Those categories of personal data are considered to be sensitive data, so called special categories of data.

V. Contacts: When you save contacts in TeamViewer, TeamViewer GmbH will receive your contacts. Please be mindful that contacts saved may contain personal data of third parties, which may not be aware that you saved them in TeamViewer.

Files and Other Content: If you use TeamViewer to send files to other participants in a connection, the App will require access to files stored locally on the device. This may be configured using device settings to enable and disable such access. Any files are shared only between participants of a connection are not stored by TeamViewer GmbH.

If you do not grant permission to access to the device folder, the App will not process the folder data. Please note that you may not be able to use this feature if you do not grant us permission to access the folder.

Similarly, any content exchanged between parties during a TeamViewer connection such as screen sharing is not stored by TeamViewer GmbH.

### B. Data Usage

TeamViewer GmbH is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of TeamViewer as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the [End User License Agreement](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/) where additional information on security measures is available.

TeamViewer relies upon certain information in order to establish secure remote connections for the device or devices that you use. For each device, this information includes the Machine ID (MID), the Device ID, along with the IP address that is applicable at the start of a connection. The MID includes the MAC address, combined with other device-related information to ensure uniqueness. It is a unique identifier that allows TeamViewer master infrastructure to generate the TeamViewer Device ID and allows it to distinguish between unique user devices that have the TeamViewer products installed.

The MID, Device ID and IP address will be retained for a period of three (3) months following the end of the contractual relationship with you.

Please note that if you upload a profile picture to your TeamViewer profile, TeamViewer GmbH will retain your profile picture for as long as you are a user, unless and until you replace your profile picture. TeamViewer GmbH will not retain any copies of your profile picture.

We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

### C. Data Subjects Rights

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact [privacy@teamviewer.com](mailto:privacy@teamviewer.com).

##  **TeamViewer Privacy for TeamViewer Remote Management**

 **Introduction**

We at TeamViewer GmbH take protection of your personal data very seriously. Personal data means any information that can personally reference you, such as your name, address, email addresses, IP address, etc. The following policy provides you with information about the collection of personal data 1. in relation to the administration of the contractual relationship between you and TeamViewer GmbH, and 2. your responsible use of the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management, consisting of the TeamViewer Monitoring & Asset Management, TeamViewer Endpoint Protection and TeamViewer Backup as well as the Server Services described in the EULA (hereinafter collectively referred to as “ **TeamViewer Remote Management** ”).

## 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

A. Controller respectively Provider  
B. Data Protection Officer  
C. Categories of Data  
D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing  
E. Recipients  
F. Retention Periods for Personal Data  
G. Statutory/contractual requirement  
H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling  
I. Your Rights

## 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of TeamViewer Remote Management

A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer Remote Management  
B. Data Usage  
C. Data Subjects Rights

## 1\. Data Protection Information concerning your contractual Relationship with TeamViewer

###  **A. Controller respectively Provider**

TeamViewer GmbH, Jahnstraße 30, 73037 Göppingen (“ **TeamViewer** ”), is your contractual partner and controller of your personal data in accordance with Art. 4 para. 7 General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) and § 13 German Telemedia Act concerning the entering into and administering the contractual relationship with you. For information on data processing in relation to your responsible use of the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management as well as the Server Services as described in the EULA please refer to the information concerning the use of TeamViewer .

###  **B. Data Protection Officer**

TeamViewer appointed Mr. Julian Häcker as external data protection officer, who can be reached at dsb-teamviewer@ensecur.de or at ENSECUR GmbH, to the attention of Mr. Julian Häcker, Rotebühlplatz 20A, 70173 Stuttgart.

###  **C. Categories of Data**

#### I. Use of TeamViewer Product:

With regard to personal information collected when you download and use our TeamViewer product, please refer to the TeamViewer product privacy policy.

#### II. Signing up for TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you sign up for TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer collects your name, email address, a password of your choice, along with time, date and time zone of you signing in.

#### III. Download TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you download TeamViewer Remote Management to your computer, TeamViewer collects your IP address and name.

#### IV. License Auditing:

We will collect information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer Remote Management.

###  **D. Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing**

#### I. Download:

When you download TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer processes your personal data to provide you with the option to use TeamViewer Remote Management. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined above under C. I. is a user agreement concerning the use of TeamViewer Remote Management, i.e. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### II. Signing up for TeamViewer Remote Management:

When you sign up to TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer uses your personal data for the administration and enhancement of the contract with you. Legal basis to process your personal data outlined under C. II. is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

#### III. License Auditing:

TeamViewer is using information about the frequency of your use of TeamViewer Remote Management in order to monitor if the agreed license restrictions are observed and in case we recognize that they are exceeded, we will contact you to suggest changing your license type. Legal basis for processing your personal data outlined under C. III is Art. 6 para. 1 lit b) GDPR.

###  **E. Recipients**

TeamViewer has strong technical and organizational security measures to protect personal data against unauthorized disclosure and to ensure that only relevant individuals, which act within their job description and have a need to know interest in accessing personal data, will have access to your personal data. TeamViewer employees, who administer and enhance the contractual relationship with you will receive access to your personal data. If you have a paid subscription, employees who are concerned with processing such transactions will receive access to your data. In case you contact our support, our employees who are engaged in providing support will handle your personal data to the extent required to answer your request.

However, we also instruct third parties, such IT maintenance and storage service provider, to help us to operate our business. These third party providers may receive access to personal data through the service they provide. TeamViewer has chosen these third parties with due care and obligated them to confidentiality. Should you have any questions about third parties we use, please contact us at privacy@teamviewer.com.

We will not share your personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

Where TeamViewer transfers your personal data out of the EU or the EEA to countries that do not have an adequate level of data protection recognized by the EU, for example to receive group internal IT services from Australia, US and Armenia, we will apply safeguards to adequately protect your personal data. Please refer to [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN) to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries under Directive 95/46/EC, or to <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework> to obtain a copy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

In the context of the provision of TeamViewer Remote Management, employees of TeamViewer’s affiliate Monitis LLC, located in Armenia (address: 9 Alek Manukyan St, Yerevan 0070, Armenia), may also have access to certain metadata and to data about the usage of the TeamViewer Remote Management for the purpose of performing analysis to improve and develop the TeamViewer Remote Management. Furthermore, employees from Monitis LLC may, in limited cases, provide you with support and thus receive access to your personal data. Additionally, employees of Hotjar Ltd, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta, may receive your personal data to analyze user behavior of TeamViewer Remote Management users.

###  **F. Retention Periods for Personal Data**

TeamViewer retains your personal data for the duration of our contractual relationship with you, regardless if your subscription is for free or paid. Once this contractual relationship terminates, TeamViewer will delete your personal data, unless TeamViewer is legally obligated to retain personal data such as your name, your order form, and the date of the order, in accordance with § 257 German Commercial Code and/or § 147 German Tax Code for a minimum of six and a maximum of ten years, if you payed for TeamViewer. Personal data that we collect in order to carry out license auditing will be deleted three (3) months after the defined license auditing period has elapsed.

###  **G. Statutory/contractual requirement**

You may choose not to provide your personal data or provide incomplete personal data. However, you should be aware that you may not be able to engage in a contractual relationship with us or receive adequate support.

###  **H. Automatic Decision-making and Profiling**

TeamViewer does not use your personal data for automatic decision-making and profiling.

###  **I. Your Rights**

You may contact us either in writing or by email at datarequest@teamviewer.com in order to exercise the following rights to the extent your entitled to so under applicable law:

  * You may access your personal data to check and review such data;
  * You may request a copy of your personal data;
  * You may demand that we supplement, correct or delete your personal data; or cease or restrict the collection, processing, use or disclosure of your personal data; the right of rectification also comprises the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement;
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data;
  * You may request to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and – subject to your acquisition of the respective copyrights or other required rights – have it transmitted to another controller, provided that the processing is based on your respective consent or to execute a contractual relationship or a relationship prior to entering into a contract with you.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of your personal data. In order to file a complaint, please contact the supervisory authority competent for your place of residency or alternatively, you may contact “Der Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und die Informationsfreiheit, Königstraße 10a, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany“.

Should you have any questions on the processing of your personal data by TeamViewer in relation to your contractual relationship, please contact privacy@teamviewer.com.

## 2\. Information concerning your responsible use of TeamViewer Remote Management

When you use TeamViewer Remote Management, we are providing the product to you as a technical service that you may reasonably use. We technically assist you, as a processor, with the use of the platform for your TeamViewer Remote Management devices. You are responsible for utilizing TeamViewer in accordance with the applicable laws, including data protection laws. The following section explains to you how TeamViewer Remote Management works.

###  **A. Personal Data processed through your use of TeamViewer Remote Management**

TeamViewer Remote Management is a tool integrated in the TeamViewer product, with which you can monitor your IT infrastructure, such as hardware and software, keep your computers clean and save with anti-malware, and/or remotely restore and save your data to a cloud via disk to cloud backup. In order to use TeamViewer Remote Management, you must have subscribed to our TeamViewer product, as TeamViewer Remote Management is only available for in-product use.

While providing TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer may receive personal data from the devices monitored. Depending on your usage of TeamViewer Remote Management, TeamViewer may receive different categories of personal data. However, due to end-to-end encryption, we are not able to access your content. The following paragraph outlines the categories of data processed.

 **Monitoring** – provides checks on disk space, disk health, CPU usage, antivirus software, windows update, memory usage, Windows firewall, online state, event logs, windows service, processes online status, disk health memory It provides remote task management, alerts and email notifications.

 **Asset Management** – creates an inventory of deployed hardware including type, name of hardware, descriptive text, vendor and software including version and modification date of installed and licensed components. Provides reporting functionality to cover hardware and software inventory. Personal information may be processed as part of collecting name of hardware. We recommend that hardware should be named anonymously or according to configuration item standards to ensure that personal information is not collected by TeamViewer Remote Management.

 **Endpoint Protection** – provides real-time protection for files and automated scanning of devices such as removable media to identify potential threats. Personal information collected is limited to emails that are used to provide alerts and notifications of anti-malware scans.

 **Backup** – provides functional to perform network backups controlled by backup policies, file selection and file exclusion, automatic deduplication, alerts for failed Backups and remote support through TeamViewer product. Backup functionality uses the Zoolz cloud service provided by Genie9 Ltd 32 Woodstock Grove Shepherds Bush London W12 8LE, United Kingdom with storage using Amazon Web Services located in Ireland.

Personal information may be contained within content subject to backup and restoration activities.

###  **B. Data Usage**

TeamViewer is using all of the personal data described in section II. A. in order to provide you with the functionalities of TeamViewer Remote Management as agreed in the End User License Agreement and the Performance Specification and in accordance with the data processing provisions in section C. of the End User License Agreement where additional information on security measures is available.

TeamViewer Remote Management functionality supports remote management of devices across a network. The personal data processed when you use TeamViewer Remote Management is stored on servers hosted by Amazon Web Services in Ireland. We will not share personal data with local authorities or courts except where we are required to do so by applicable law, a court order or a legally binding injunction.

###  **C. Data subjects Rights**

Data subjects may exercise certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal data through TeamViewer towards you. As your technical service provider we may assist you to answer such request as described in the data processing agreement in section C of the End User License Agreement. Such rights might be accessing personal data, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, data portability and objection to the processing. Data subjects have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in relation to the processing of their personal data.

Should you have any questions on the processing of personal data through TeamViewer, please contact privacy@teamviewer.com.
